Kevin Luke Martin

07955482627 thescience15@googlemail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

A software developer with 4 years commercial experience currently seeking a role that relates to my interest in PHP and ReactJS. Previously worked in web engineering and agile environments, contributed suggestions on renovating one's legacy system, meeting deadlines, adding time slot data in a new page for their new system. I am constantly learning by maintaining my applications, an online neural network to recognise images sent from my android app via STOMP sockets to a server. Moreover I have learned modern frameworks including Angular and Spring through online courses and am eager to learn more.

SKILL SET

- JavaEE
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/TypeScript
- MYSQL
- Android/REST/okhttp3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Level Entry Developer - Open GI - 2022 to 2024

Open Gi provides web services for brokers allowing larger access to products and policies. Worked with the ecommerce team, starting with their mapper system OpenQuote uses to translate soap risk so the system can communicate with our partnered company, Mobius. Moved on to other projects including amending on their ebroker site, such as adding previous addresses. Roles included modifying their UI to meet requirements via TypeScript to retrieve, creating SQL queries to search for errors and issues, backend processing, validation.

Junior Developer - Transalis - 2019 to 2020

Transalis connects suppliers with their customers via EDI software to allow fast and easy transference of transaction files between suppliers (our clients) and trading partners, such as John Lewis, Tesco, Asda etc. My roles involved accessing Transalis's server via remote desktop, running a batch script to create a new profile for the client and/or configure the routing between the trading partner and our server by altering another batch script. Then email the trading partner asking to send a test order via AS2. Want back to university to enrol in a masters degree in creative technologies mid 2020.

Java Developer - Stannah - 2017 to 2018

This was a placement during my undergraduate course. Worked in an agile environment, with daily standup meetings with a team. My role was to develop a screen for stairlift engineers to log their jobs and time slots and check with masternaut's REST API, as well as tasks and bugs on the HR and sales screen to sum and display order costs. While developing business logic I would perform the calculations to verify the code. Learned freemarker template (FTL), groovy, and MVC pattern, groovy business logic, model data, entityQuery apache Ofbiz. Returned to level 6 of university in 2019.

INTERESTS

Web Development

Started Developing websites using Java EE with Tomcat, Sprint Boot and C#, for learning purposes in my spare time. Websites that can communicate with each other via REST APIs. Also JWT token authorization and STOMP sockets to create a chatting application. Currently maintaining my secure website which interacts with my portfolio to secure and supply logs, and is also where I have adapted my neural network to recognise images.

Games

Enjoy playing video games and would like to create my own one day. Especially 3D games with puzzles such as Zelda. They help bring out the social side in me and would also like to work in a games shop to help customers make decisions.

3D Graphics/Computer Vision and Robotics

Developed some low poly models on the 3D modelling software Blender and have experimented with Raycasts, Vectors, webGL and camera rotation using trigonometry sine and cosine laws in Unity3D. Moreover, I have experimented with a Raspberry Pi computer to detect motion using a Raspberry Pi camera module and OpenCV on Python.

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth - 2020 to 2021

Postgraduate diploma in Creative Technologies: PASS

Developed a reinforcement learning agent that reacts to the players actions. Learned how to develop a game loop per frame, render a canvas to a frame with Java's Swing library, multidimensional arrays. The project idea was a q-learning that acknowledges its states or observations of combat actions the player performs, and will learn to defend and attack based on the damage taken during the level.

University of Portsmouth – 2015 to 2019

BSc (Hons) Computing: 2:1

Developed understanding of OOP and the 4 concepts of the paradigm as well as web development, networking protocols, Remote procedure call and databases. Dynamic website built with servlets and JSPs that connects to a MYSQL database via direct Java connection. My final year project was a mobile app allowing users to code on their phones by drawing patterns which are put through a neural network to determine a block of generic code, like a class, method etc. This was intended as a faster method to code on a mobile device.

Achievements

• Developed a 2D game in python for a competition and won 2nd tier.

Highbury College – 2015

Mathematics (GCSE) - A*

During my A Levels and BTEC in Portsmouth College, I studied higher tier Mathematics because I enjoy algebra and was put in foundation tier in school. Achieved an A star, and 100% on unit 2.

Portsmouth College – 2013 to 2015 Creative Media (Games Development) - DISTINCTION STAR Applied Science, ICT - B, C